<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Samarth Bhaskar</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2015 21:58:35 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2015 21:58:35 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Problem of Value - Economics as a Moral Science</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;420&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://vimeo.com/122591452&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple of weeks ago, the New York Review of Books Foundation held a conference, primarily composed of panels, about economics. The title of the conference was “What’s Wrong with the Economy and with Economics?” The conference featured academics and public intellectuals giving short talks and engaging in debates about modern day macro-economic trends. All the videos from the conference are available on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nybooks.com/blogs/gallery/2015/mar/29/whats-wrong-with-the-economy/&quot;&gt;NYRB&lt;/a&gt; site. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started by watching a panel on The Problem of Value: Economics as a Moral Science. This &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/122591452&quot;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt; features a panel moderated by Itamar Rabinovich, with talks by Greta Brochmann from the University of Oslo, Richard Sennett of NYU and Jeremy Waldron also of NYU. Each speaker gave a short talk on their interpretation of the place of &amp;quot;value&amp;quot; in economic analysis. They all had different takes on the topic, but each I enjoyed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I liked Brochmann&amp;#39;s talk the best because it presented the most concise and comprehensive review of Scandinavian welfare societies I&amp;#39;ve ever come across. She had a great model to present about how the Scandinavian model came to be. What values from its past it incorporated, how it is being challenged in modern day Norway, Sweden, etc and the onset of immigration and their new relationship with the EU. Her approach to this question was much more tactical and micro-econ based, but I think it made the strongest case for the inclusion of moralistic frameworks in econ policy by the state. Econ is often characterized as a faceless, emotionless, humanity-less science - but if framed properly it can be undeniably human, touching every part of the human experience in modern society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Richard Sennett&amp;#39;s talk was also interesting but for a different reason. He focused on the effect of new economic forces on young people&amp;#39;s valuation and formation of a career and life. This is a particularly pertinent topic for me, at the start of my career. And although I agree with him that things are very different now than they have been ever before (for new members of the workforce), I didn&amp;#39;t come away with some new understanding of how economics was going to help address these changes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/2015/03/31/economics-as-moral-science/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2015/03/31/economics-as-moral-science/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Kendrick Lamar - To Pimp a Butterfly</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Earlier this week, Kendrick Lamar released his much anticipated and long-awaited follow up to &amp;quot;good kid, m.A.A.d city,&amp;quot; called &amp;quot;To Pimp a Butterfly.&amp;quot; The album has been showered with early praise. Lamar has done a few interviews, including this one in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2015/03/22/arts/music/kendrick-lamar-on-his-new-album-and-the-weight-of-clarity.html?_r=0&amp;amp;pagewanted=all&quot;&gt;New York Times&lt;/a&gt; that situates him among &amp;quot;prophetic witnesses&amp;quot; like Sam Cooke, Marvin Gaye, and Curtis Mayfield. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve listened to the album a handful of times in the last couple of days and it has yet to lose its effect. Albums (or films, or books, or really anything) that are highly anticipated often don&amp;#39;t live up to the hype. There have been only a few moments in the last few years when something I have high expectations for ends up meeting and surpassing those expectations. After whetting my appetite earlier this year with &amp;quot;Blacker the Berry&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Untitled&amp;quot; (performed only on &lt;a href=&quot;http://thecolbertreport.cc.com/videos/pjrqsj/kendrick-lamar&quot;&gt;Colbert Report&lt;/a&gt;), Lamar has accomplished a rare and difficult feat; his album has met and surpassed high expectations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aesthetically, the album delivers. Lamar invites legends like George Clinton, flows over beats by Flying Lotus, invites sublime singers like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0SJIgTLe0hc&quot;&gt;Lalah Hathaway&lt;/a&gt;, samples Sufjan Stevens and brings in some of the best jazz riffs I&amp;#39;ve heard in hip hop in a while. The album is well-balanced, it ebbs and flows to keep your attention but doesn&amp;#39;t seem to compromise in production quality. Each track stands well on its own but is elevated as an ensemble album.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that is only the honey with which Lamar attracts the listener. Behind this beautiful music is the story of Kendrick Lamar in the last few years. His battles with depression, survivor&amp;#39;s guilt, success, fame and the strong weight of responsibility as he has become more famous and more powerful. Lamar is the post-modern artist we&amp;#39;ve been blessed with. Like James Baldwin in his time, Lamar struggles out loud with the contradictions in his life. With his inability to draw a clear narrative arc through his upbringing in Compton and now his new found success as an internationally touring artist. And like Baldwin, and Langston Hughes and other worthy comparisons, Lamar expresses all of these feelings in his poetry. And like those predecessors, Lamar isn&amp;#39;t interested in distancing himself from his upbringing, even though his life now couldn&amp;#39;t be any more different. Lamar is trying, with all his might, to take what he&amp;#39;s been given, think and write critically about what that means for him, for his community, and come up with some answers about how he can bring all this back together. The prophetic preachers of soul and hip hop&amp;#39;s past have been fighting this battle from the pulpit of fame for generations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This album has signs of maturity that were not present in &amp;quot;good kid, m.A.A.d city.&amp;quot; If that album was a day in the life of 25 year old Lamar, this album is deeper look at a young adult coming to terms with growing up. He struggles, at once, with being a hypocrite, but also needing to build self-confidence to survive in a competitive world. These struggles are not too different from what Kanye West has been going through in recent years. But Kanye&amp;#39;s resolution has been different. His focus has been on high art and on high culture. Kendrick, on the other hand, is squarely situated in popular culture. For my money, I&amp;#39;d much rather hear a man describe his struggle for meaning in every day life than trying to find meaning in some higher, more philosophical milieu. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/2015/03/17/kendrick-lamar-to-pimp-a-butterfly/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2015/03/17/kendrick-lamar-to-pimp-a-butterfly/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Knausgaard on immigration</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2015/03/15/magazine/karl-ove-knausgaards-passage-through-america.html?hp&amp;amp;action=click&amp;amp;pgtype=Homepage&amp;amp;module=second-column-region&amp;amp;region=top-news&amp;amp;WT.nav=top-news&amp;amp;_r=1&amp;amp;pagewanted=all&quot;&gt;part 2&lt;/a&gt; of Karl Ove Knausgaard&amp;#39;s NYTimes magazine feature, the author - most famously of a 6-part &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/My_Struggle_%28Knausg%C3%A5rd_novels%29&quot;&gt;memoir&lt;/a&gt; - writes about immigration. His assignment has been to trace the paths that Vikings and early Norwegians took in America, first arriving in Newfoundland and then settling in mainland America. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Karl Ove is still uncomfortable in America. He&amp;#39;s still unsure what to even make of his journey. But one thing is clear, his time in America is going to be spent as a Norwegian and will most likely be limited. That emotional distance allows him to think critically about American culture and American emigration. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This definition of culture, especially in the context of an American immigrant trying to assimilate, rung very true for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is culture, if not a set of prejudices? A set of unformulated and unconscious rules and ways of behavior that every member of a given society nonetheless immediately recognizes and accepts?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Karl Ove is thinking of and writing about his ancestors and older family members settling here. This is exactly the kind of cultural shift I went through as an immigrant. In fact, my family and I ended up at the end of that transition absorbing all manner of American prejudices, a lot of which were targeted right back at Indian-American immigrants. That&amp;#39;s something about immigrant communities I have never understood - how quick we are to put down other immigrants behind us in the assimilation process. What a shame, that we can&amp;#39;t extend courtesy and comfort to our compatriots, the same that we were denied merely a few years before.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/2015/03/15/knausgaard-on-immigration/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2015/03/15/knausgaard-on-immigration/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>On Kanye West and black ambition</title>
        <description>&lt;h1&gt;Kanye&amp;#39;s evolution&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/Kanye.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Kanye West&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week, Slate&amp;#39;s Arthur Chu wrote a piece called &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.salon.com/2015/02/17/kanye_west_vs_white_mediocrity_the_real_story_behind_beck_beyonce_and_snl_40/&quot;&gt;Kanye West Vs. White Mediocrity&lt;/a&gt;. This was on the heels of Kanye&amp;#39;s latest public appearences at the Grammys and SNL&amp;#39;s 40th anniversary. I had an email exchange about the topic that I&amp;#39;ll partially share here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some of this reminded me of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XZ0fRBtAB1w&quot;&gt;Chris Rock&amp;#39;s joke&lt;/a&gt; about mediocrity and black people being able to suck. He talks about how Joe Lewis (or someone) was fighting a white boxer and round after round, kicking this guy&amp;#39;s ass. And then in like the 13th round he finally knocks him out and wins the fight. When they went to the judges&amp;#39; cards, they had Joe Lewis losing the fight. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#39;s kind of an interesting argument about resource constraints or opportunity constraints elevating quality. Maybe because there are so few spots for black artists and entertainers, there&amp;#39;s an artificial constraint that&amp;#39;s created. This, in turn, elevates quality. I mean, I&amp;#39;m all for higher quality, but I think there are more humane ways to achieve rather than racism.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was thinking this during the SNL-40 show: everyone judges Kanye with a lot of baggage. During his performance I was texting with my sister (a huge Kanye fan), watching Twitter (where my networks are largely white, affluent, self-described liberals) - and I &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/samarthbhaskar/status/567168718648909825&quot;&gt;tweeted this&lt;/a&gt;. I think Chu addresses this in his article too, he said something like everyone is judging the thing he did last not what he&amp;#39;s doing right now. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Perfectionism is exhausting/stressful. For Kanye to strive for perfection, for Michael Jackson to have done that, and Nina Simone, and James Baldwin and so many other people - there&amp;#39;s a real cost for this. People are driven into exhaustion, have to leave the country, or worse they pay with their lives. It&amp;#39;s really sad that all these artists want is to express themselves, to pursue their art but once they achieve a certain level of fame, perfection is the only option anymore. And then they end up driving themselves into the ground. And we think we&amp;#39;re rewarding them with our love and adoration, but we&amp;#39;re just feeding their addiction. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I like &amp;quot;whiteness is a roomier identity.&amp;quot; That was a nice way of capturing that sentiment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I&amp;#39;ve had a change of heart about Kanye in the last year or so. I used to be the type of guy who&amp;#39;d say &amp;quot;ugh, I loved Kanye when he just stuck to backpack rap. His first few albums were so great. He should&amp;#39;ve just stuck to being a good producer.&amp;quot; I thought I was saying that as a critical consumer of his music, but I was doing exactly what this article is talking about. I was boxing him in, not allowing him to be a full person or a full artist. Now, I&amp;#39;m on board. I&amp;#39;m not uncritical, but I&amp;#39;m along for the ride. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Roxane Gay on Black Ambition&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/untamed_state.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;An Untamed State&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to my thoughts on Kanye, I&amp;#39;ve been thinking about a piece my sister shared with me by Roxane Gay. By the way, her debut novel &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/1209677063&quot;&gt;An Untamed State&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; knocked me out. In this essay, Gay talks about acheiving success in her career as a writer and educator but never feeling comfortable with it. This is a pretty familiar mental model for me. For all the success I&amp;#39;ve acheived in life, it never feels like I was meant to be successful. I have to constantly remind myself that I earned the things I&amp;#39;ve earned. Certainly not without luck, fortune and support, but also not without hard work and tenacity. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of these thoughts are present in Kanye&amp;#39;s maturation. Kanye, more than any artist I know, is fighting to make his success a normal thing. Sometimes that means he&amp;#39;s reaching for bigger, bolder things. Sometimes that means he&amp;#39;s allowing himself the freedom that other successful people might have. If Donald Trump and Mitt Romney feel they can run for president because they were successful in private enterprise, Kanye feels similiary that he should be able to try his hand at fashion because of his success as a music producer. I don&amp;#39;t know if I agree with that basic approach, but I do support Kanye&amp;#39;s ability to do that as much as Trump or Romney are able to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;David Oyelowo on Obama&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/Oyelowo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;David Oyelowo&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://the-talks.com/interviews/david-oyelowo/&quot;&gt;David Oyelowo&lt;/a&gt; had a short interview during his post-Selma press rounds where he mentioned that Obama&amp;#39;s presidency has been a boone for Black narratives, actors and projects to get attention. This is not a new idea, but I liked that he got to tell President Obama about it. Despite being a hyper rational guy, I bet it was nice for Obama to hear that. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe Kanye, Roxange Gay, David Oyelowo and Barack Obama can be the models that the next generation of artists, authors, politicians can gather inspiration from.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/2015/02/23/on-kanye-west/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2015/02/23/on-kanye-west/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ISIS follow up - Islamist power in civil war</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As a follow up to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://samarthbhaskar.com/2015/02/19/what-isis-really-wants/&quot;&gt;ISIS response&lt;/a&gt; I posted last week, here&amp;#39;s an &lt;a href=&quot;http://muse.jhu.edu/login?auth=0&amp;amp;type=summary&amp;amp;url=/journals/international_security/v039/39.3.ahmad.html&quot;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; that I came across today. The abstract below states the main conceit, which is that Islamists have a structural advantage in selling security services in the conflict security market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;In civil wars across the world, certain Islamist groups have competed exceptionally well against their rivals. The conventional wisdom points to either religion or ethnic politics to explain Islamist success. These ideological and identity-based explanations, however, tend to overlook the powerful economic influence that the local business class has over civil war outcomes. Civil war can be modeled as a market for security, wherein protection must be purchased from multiple substate rackets. Using this market model, a close investigation of the Somali case reveals why and under what conditions the interests of the profit-driven business class align with those of ideologically motivated Islamist groups. Security costs are of critical importance to businesses in a civil war, and Islamists are uniquely competitive in lowering these costs. The business-Islamist alliance is therefore driven by rational, economic considerations, which can contribute to the rise of Islamist power.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The general point made in this article comes on page 96:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Because Islamists are able to sell security across ethnic and tribal divisions, however, they can offer more competitive prices than groups that primarily sell protection to a narrower pool of prospective buyers. By charging lower margins across the board,Islamists have the ability to capture a larger share of the security market than ethnic or tribal groups. As their market share increases, they can lower their rates further to price out their rivals. Therefore, not only do Islamist groups give businesses the option to leave coercive relationships with ethnic or tribal protection rackets, but they also offer more competitive prices to do so&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This makes sense to me, and the case study of Somalia illustrates the point pretty well. Although there isn&amp;#39;t an official civil war in Syria/Iraq, citizens in the area dealing with ISIS based on rational models makes much more sense than most of the narratives in the media.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/2015/02/23/islamist-power-in-civil-war/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2015/02/23/islamist-power-in-civil-war/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Response to &quot;What ISIS really wants&quot;</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Atlantic had a cover story last month, which now looks to be deprecated. But here&amp;#39;s a &lt;a href=&quot;http://webcache.googleusercontent.com/search?q=cache:http://www.theatlantic.com/features/archive/2015/02/what-isis-really-wants/384980/&quot;&gt;cached version&lt;/a&gt;. The story was about ISIS and its religious underpinnings. My friend Arjun and I discussed it over email last night and I wanted to share some of my thoughts here. I&amp;#39;ve pasted my email to him below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Princeton professor is a cool guy. If I remember correctly, he came to UIUC when I was studying Arabic/Middle Eastern studies and I enjoyed hearing him talk. There was a dude at UIUC who was very similar to him. Secular authority on Islam and Islamic history. The UIUC guy, Khalil, had some interesting things to say - he felt like he had to change the course of his research and scholarship to be more radicalism focused in order to compete for tenure track jobs. I think he was much more interested in other things about the Muslim world, but so it goes, I guess.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I think the author if this Atlantic piece did a pretty good job explaining major tenets of Islam. I was glad to see he differentiated (with some help from Haykel) between Islam and Muslims.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As he mentioned, the slow and protracted decline of ISIS is most likely what will happen, but what I’m interested in is what a future Islamic state looks like. Saudi has lost favor as the one true Islamic nation. Iran doesn’t get counted because is Shia. But I’m curious if there will be a future state that’ll be the Muslim equivalent of Israel. Israel was founded on very similar grounds. Zionism espouses some of the same tenets as al-Baghdadi’s Salafism. But Zionism, at least in its most severe form, turned out to be untenable (politically, economically, etc) for Israel, so they went down a more moderate road. [^1] Certainly they had the US’s backing, which helped them survive. I wonder if ISIS will find some sort of moderate version of itself too.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One thing that I thought was missing from this article was a sense of scale. In fact, that’s something I’ve had a hard time grasping anywhere. I don’t know if we’re talking about 500K citizens, a million, 10M? Talking to some strong advocates can have the unintended effect of making the movement seem a lot bigger in scale than it is. But again, I know they control a huge &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2014/06/12/world/middleeast/the-iraq-isis-conflict-in-maps-photos-and-video.html?_r=0&amp;amp;pagewanted=all&quot;&gt;swathe&lt;/a&gt; of territory between Syria and Iraq but I don’t know how many people we’re talking about. Part of me thinks that there’s some natural ceiling that they’ll hit, after which they’ll have to start becoming more moderate. Because creating social services, a viable economy, etc for a group of thousands is very different than doing that for hundreds of thousands.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dave Chappelle had a really funny joke about ISIS/radical Islam on Monday night when I saw him. He was like “ISIS is like the Tupac of religions. It’s like “YO WHAT, I GO SO HARD MOTHERF**. COME AT ME.” It’s hard to convey over email, but he captured the sentiment really well. And like Tupac, at least younger Tupac, that level of bravado is something that goes away with age. Maybe ISIS will mature out of this stage. Unfortunately their “immaturity” manifests in severed heads, slaves, beaten women, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The author’s description of his conversations with the English and Australian extremists was really interesting. When people betray a strong confidence, have an answer to everything and can convince you, I find that really fascinating. I’m not that confident about anything in my life. I almost envy it. They’ve bought into it wholesale. Muslim communities in the US and elsewhere are having a hard time counteracting online recruitment of young men and women. It’s hard to come back to “we have a strong and principled view about everything” with “well, things are complicated.” It’s not as convincing an argument.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[^1]: that’s probably one of the only times you’ll hear me describe Israel as moderate.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/2015/02/19/what-isis-really-wants/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2015/02/19/what-isis-really-wants/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Some thoughts on newsroom analytics</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently left my job at &lt;a href=&quot;www.etsy.com&quot;&gt;Etsy&lt;/a&gt; as a data analyst to join the newsroom at the &lt;a href=&quot;www.nytimes.com&quot;&gt;New York Times&lt;/a&gt;. In addition to being sad to leave Etsy, and learning &lt;em&gt;a lot&lt;/em&gt; in my 2 years there, I&amp;#39;m very excited to work with talented journalists and technologists at the Times to help usher the organization into a new era. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve only made it to day-2 but I thought I&amp;#39;d take a moment to write down some thoughts about starting on this new endeavor. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Innovation Report and audience development&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The team I am joining, Audience Development, was born out of the leaked, and much discussed, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scribd.com/doc/224608514/The-Full-New-York-Times-Innovation-Report&quot;&gt;innovation report&lt;/a&gt;. Taking a hard look at the competitive news industry, the NYT decided to set some difficult goals and make some changes. The business side (subscription, ads, finance) of the organization has long used experiments, data analysis and similar empirical tools to make decisions. The newsroom is working on building up the same competencies for news decisions. Analytics, as it happens, is one of these competencies. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Among the many things I have to learn&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What the NYTimes is about and how to think critically about the news consumer. I was able to advocate for the Etsy user pretty well after my 2 years there; thanks in large part to many experiments, user research and tons of data analysis. I would like to learn about and advocate for the NYT news reader in the same way.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;How does the NYTimes plan on carrying its success in high quality journalism over to the digital age. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Because I joined the analyst team at Etsy near its beginning, I was helped with a wide variety of projects and products. I think I have a similar opportunity in joining the newsroom analytics team at its beginning at the Times. I&amp;#39;m eager to see what parts of the newsroom could benefit from studying user behavior in making their work better. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Web experiments have had a &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.okcupid.com/index.php/we-experiment-on-human-beings/&quot;&gt;controversial&lt;/a&gt; year, but I still believe they&amp;#39;re the best way to assess causality. Finding a smart and appropriate way to bring experiments into the newsroom will be a challenge. At the onset, though, I believe there&amp;#39;s a place for it in the newsroom and it can be done successfully. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;At Etsy, we were pretty lucky to have clear metrics of success. The more sales we could generate for our sellers, the better. A similar &amp;quot;north star&amp;quot; metric is harder to point out in news consumption. I&amp;#39;m sure many at the Times and in the industry have thought critically about this, but it doesn&amp;#39;t seem obvious to me yet. In fact, I think the lack of a clear metric of success is often what derails analytics projects. I&amp;#39;d like to avoid getting derailed by the wrong metrics.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Onward!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m excited to take on this challenge. I&amp;#39;m passionate about seeing the NYTimes survive into the digital age. I&amp;#39;m convinced that the type of journalistic expertise the Times has developed over its 150 year history deserves an audience in our new media landscape. And I&amp;#39;m thankful to have learned what I learned in the last 2 years to help me get started.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/2015/01/27/some-thoughts-on-newsroom-analytics/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2015/01/27/some-thoughts-on-newsroom-analytics/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A few words about my experience at MAPSS, UChicago</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Someone approached me &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Talmudist/status/492464737351790592&quot;&gt;on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; a few days ago with some questions about &lt;a href=&quot;http://mapss.uchicago.edu/&quot;&gt;MAPSS&lt;/a&gt;. We had a short email exchange recently that I thought I&#39;d share on here in case other incoming MAPSS students are interested in learning about my experience there. This is, obviously, just one anecdote about what MAPSS is like, but hopefully readers can gather some insights to inform their decisions or expectations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi [redacted], &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Happy to help answer questions. I&#39;ll take them in turn, below.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Firstly, regarding cost: I totally agree with you. It&#39;s an, almost prohibitively, expensive program. I was very naive at the time of application and didn&#39;t really consider that too much. Now I&#39;m glad I went forward with it because my life wouldn&#39;t be the same without the training I received at MAPSS. But if I were faced with the same decision again, and I soberly assessed my probabilities of success, I don&#39;t know if I could make the same call as a rational man. I&#39;m glad I got lucky and fell at the tail end of that probability of success and can now afford to pay my student loans :-).&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_extra&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gmail_quote&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;im&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;gmail_quote&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;1. If you don&#39;t mind being frank, when and why did you decide not to pursue a PhD? &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt; I took a couple of the first year PhD courses along with the first year PhD students who were starting in poli sci. It was clear to me right away that these students were better theorists, writers, thinkers than me. They came to MAPSS with better training, had written better undergraduate theses and were way better read than me. I knew I would have to play a lot of catch-up to get to their level, all the while they would be getting even sharper with access to tenured advisors, reading and writing just like I was.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;One of the first year requirements for poli sci PhDs was a course called &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://political-science.uchicago.edu/academics/courses.shtml&quot;&gt;Data Analysis&lt;/a&gt;,&quot; which was basically an intro into empirical reasoning. I found myself really enjoying discussions in that class, and we got a quick taste for statistical data analysis. I also talked a lot with my preceptor at that time about taking methods courses. My preceptor was honest about the positive experiences she had in methods courses and about how she was seeing her colleagues who were methodologists really succeed in the field. Combined with seeing what kinds of papers were making it into top journals, being a middle east studies student and not really finding [redacted] or [redacted] that impressive (&lt;a href=&quot;http://political-science.uchicago.edu/people/faculty/wedeen.shtml&quot;&gt;Lisa Wedeen&lt;/a&gt;, unfortunately, was away that semester) and not really being super enthusiastic about writing about civil war and terrorism (that&#39;s what other ME poli sci people were writing about) - I pivoted to methods work.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;I still ended up writing my thesis about middle east topics, but with more emphasis on statistical methods I used to push forward my argument.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;im&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;gmail_quote&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;2. Did you have a significant quant background before attending MAPSS? I also come from a Poli Sci/Poli Theory background...I was wondering how abrupt and difficult the transition was to more quant-oriented courses. &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;I had no quantitative background before coming in to MAPSS. I, like a lot of people in the social sciences, never considered myself a &quot;math person.&quot; I attended math camp before classes started and realized that I actually was better at remembering and applying concepts from high school than most of my peers. That was a heartening step, and boosted my confidence to take methods courses. &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;While taking methods courses I frequented office hours (TA&#39;s and professor&#39;s) often. I also, almost always, completed problem sets as part of a group. I found it really frustrating to run into walls by myself and not know how to move on. But in groups, running into walls seemed less daunting. I&#39;m certain I wouldn&#39;t have been as successful at those problem sets or methods work in general if it wasn&#39;t for classmate, TA and professor support.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;I also found programing in R and Latex to be a fun exercise. It was my first time working with a low level programming language like R and the syntactical sugar of Latex was a fun challenge to work at. A few of my classmates hated coding, so they had a much harder time finishing problem sets and getting the most out of the course.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;im&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;gmail_quote&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;3. What is your experience of U Chicago&#39;s career services and alumni network? Did you avail yourself of those connections? &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;I tried to use career services often, especially at the beginning of my time at MAPSS. The designated MAPSS career counselor, [redacted], was helpful but quickly directed me toward the larger career center. They basically sent me off to job fairs, and directed me to job sites like Idealist. Partially my own fault for not being more clear, but I never found career services (at UChicago or my undergraduate institution) to be very helpful. I think if you have a clear idea of what you want (&quot;I want to go to law school&quot; or &quot;I want to be a management consultant&quot;), these types of services can be more useful. &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Since I graduated, it seems to me that MAPSS has really gone much further in this area. [Redacted] (current MAPSS career counselor) has organized a lot successful programs (including the one where you caught &lt;a href=&quot;http://samarthbhaskar.wordpress.com/2013/05/31/uchicago-mapss-alumni-talk/&quot;&gt;my talk&lt;/a&gt;) and seems to have a much better approach to answering these questions, from what I can gather. &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;im&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;gmail_quote&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;4. What was your time at MAPSS like? Did you involve yourself in extracurriculars at all? Did you socialize a great deal with your MAPSS Cohort?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;My time at MAPSS was very stressful, but overall the best intellectual growth opportunity I could&#39;ve asked for. I lived in Wicker Park, away from campus, which was hugely helpful. An hour commute separating me from the stress and tension of coursework, writing a thesis, intense classroom debate, etc was very necessary. It allowed me to carve a life outside of MAPSS, spend time with people who knew nothing about my graduate work and didn&#39;t care about it and give my brain a break every night for a couple of hours. My peers at MAPSS, who lived in Hyde Park, all hung out with each other, all complained and gossiped about the same coursework, long hours, professors, etc. I think this had deleterious effects on their ability to perform at a high level and keep a clear mind about their goals.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;I sang with the University choir a few nights a week, which was a nice break from course/thesis work as well. I spent many hours in the libraries, like others, but I tried to treat it like a job. I would arrive early in the morning and work as much as possible before, between and after courses, but I would wrap up and go home for dinner. I have some close friends from my MAPSS cohort, although they represent many disciplines beyond poli sci. I mostly spent time with them grabbing a drink after an evening class, or attending workshops together, or seeing a talk on campus. Oddly enough, most of the people I spent many hours in the library with, working on problem sets, I&#39;m not close with anymore. Take that however you will, ha.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;im&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;gmail_quote&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;5. Do you have any tips or recommendations regarding the MAPSS experience that you would impart to someone beginning the program?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;I think it&#39;s really important to set goals for yourself and keep yourself oriented toward those goals. That&#39;s not to say goals can&#39;t change, or that you need to know what you&#39;re doing on day 1, but 9-12 months is a very short time and UChicago is an immense place. Your intellectual curiosity can last you forever, but that won&#39;t help you figure out what you want to do once the program ends. I was lucky to figure out that I didn&#39;t want to apply to PhD programs after, so I focused on finding employment. I decided that I didn&#39;t want to let my thesis bleed over into the summer, that I wanted to take that time to find a job, so I worked to finish my thesis by March. I wouldn&#39;t have been able to do that if I didn&#39;t know way back in September that that was a goal for me. My preceptor, advisors and peers were able to help keep me on track because I made it clear from the onset that I wanted to meet every deadline and stay on track to finish my thesis by March. I also picked courses accordingly so the work I was doing for those courses could help me advance my thesis. Almost every chapter of my thesis came from papers I wrote for other classes. This was crucial in helping me workshop each part with a different scholar, and not double my work at the end. &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Although it&#39;s very important to stay focused on your ultimate goal, you&#39;d be remiss to miss opportunities that UChicago has to offer that are basically only available at UChicago. I saw many amazing speakers, attended lots of great workshops, spent time in office hours with great scholars and got to know a lot of peers. These are things, I believe, you can do without straying from your own goals. They enhance the experience so much more than a 80 or 90 page thesis that shows the sum total of your knowledge about one topic.  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Sorry if I rambled on a bit here, I mostly meant to say everything that was on my mind without filtering too much. I imagine you have lots of ideas about these things yourself, so you can take or leave as much or as little as you&#39;d like from this.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;All the best as you prepare for the busy year ahead! I&#39;m sure you&#39;ll have a great experience!&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2014 08:24:48 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/grad%20school/2014/07/29/a-few-words-about-my-experience-at-mapss-uchicago/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/grad%20school/2014/07/29/a-few-words-about-my-experience-at-mapss-uchicago/</guid>
        
        
        <category>grad school</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>An unsolicited thought about Soylent</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://samarthbhaskar.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/soylent.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-1056 aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;assets/soylent.jpg?w=226&quot; alt=&quot;soylent&quot; width=&quot;226&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ran across a lot of chatter about &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.portraitsincreativity.com/maira-kalman&quot;&gt;Soylent&lt;/a&gt; today, around the internet and with my friends. I&#39;m curious about the stuff, but I think there is something sort of troubling about the very idea too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, I &lt;a href=&quot;http://samarthbhaskar.com/post/my-love-for-culinary-tourism&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;love&lt;/em&gt; food&lt;/a&gt; a lot. So I mostly consider Soylent an affront to my personal and emotional attachment to experiencing food. I mean, I&#39;m mostly joking, but I&#39;m also sort of serious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also understand that Soylent is meant to serve as a supplement for people who find taking time out of their day to prepare, obtain and consume food annoying. The fact that Soylent was created by, is being championed by, and largely funded by the tech community is not coincidence. Tech, in my ways, infantilizes its members. There are many fantasies in tech that culminate with an engineer or coder being some sort of hyper-efficient programmer, only capable of one thing. The fact that major tech companies offer to do your laundry, feed you on site and give you a ride from home to work is not unrelated. There is some ideal at work underneath all of this that when you were young your parents took care of all these needs and now your company (your new parent) can take care of it. It might be a stretch, but a beige, tasteless substance that meets your every nutritional need is not too far from what your mother provides for you after birth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But even all of that isn&#39;t what bothers me about Soylent. What worries me is that Soylent was able to raise nearly &lt;a href=&quot;http://venturebeat.com/2013/06/21/soylent-crowdfunding-campaign-attracts-755k-so-people-can-survive-without-food/&quot;&gt;$1 million on Kickstarter&lt;/a&gt;. What worries me is that the likes of Andreesen Horowitz are &lt;a href=&quot;http://techcrunch.com/2013/10/21/soylent/&quot;&gt;investing money&lt;/a&gt; in it. I think this is what takes Soylent from some project to work around a human&#39;s need for food or aesthetic pleasure in experiencing food, to something that becomes a commodity for investment. I don&#39;t think Andreesen Horowitz look at a product like this and glance over its potential application as a complete replacement for food not just for engineers but everyone. I can see a future when governments&#39; with food aid programs look to Soylent as some sort of solution to hunger and malnutrition crises. It&#39;s not hard to imagine a rationale that flows something like -- &quot;well people are dying of hunger around the world, give them Soylent, *claps dusty hands*, my job here is done.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that&#39;s not what solving the problem of malnutrition is about. It&#39;s not that &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Malthusian_catastrophe#Criticism&quot;&gt;we don&#39;t have enough food&lt;/a&gt; to feed the world&#39;s hungry, it&#39;s that we&#39;re really bad at distributing food equitably. Even if we see a problem like malnutrition or starvation being solved by something like Soylent - then what? What will these people, who have been saved from the edge of starvation do? Will they have access to education? Will they be given a chance to find a job that pays enough of a salary to survive? Will they have the opportunity to find housing in a place of their choosing? What favor have we done them by keeping them alive with Soylent? More likely, will we walk away feeling like we&#39;ve done our job by giving them Soylent so their basal nutritional needs are met while we could care less about needs that come after that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have no intention of painting this picture as the actual or even presumed intentions of the inventors of Soylent. I don&#39;t think they or their investors see this as the problem they&#39;re solving. I don&#39;t have a hard time believing that the inventors of Soylent, their investors and all who are enthusiastic about the product genuinely believe it will be something office workers use as a substitute to walking out and getting an fat laden sandwich for lunch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I do believe, as &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/The-Technological-Society-Jacques-Ellul/dp/0394703901/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1406082811&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=jacques+ellul&quot;&gt;Jacques Ellul&lt;/a&gt; believed, that technological progress is irreversible. With the exception of the nuclear weapon, society has never reversed the forward movement of technology. So to go blindly on the path of innovation, to try and disrupt everything, to invent for the sake of invention carries with it another responsibility. I think it is the responsibility of the inventor, of the investor, of the problem solver to consider his/her innovation in a broader social context. And I think this is what ultimately bothers me about Soylent. There is a lack of imagination on the part of the inventors to consider what the idea of &lt;em&gt;food replacement&lt;/em&gt; actually means. Food is a &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Food_studies&quot;&gt;huge part of culture&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://imgflip.com/i/aj0ba&quot;&gt;Once cannot simply&lt;/a&gt; replace its nutritional functions and walk away scot free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Addendum: my friend &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mikearpaia/status/491875612454178816&quot;&gt;Mike asked on twitter&lt;/a&gt;, &quot;should one not solve problems when they exist?&quot; I think this is an apt question and worth an answer longer than 140 characters. In my head, this is how I think about the problem. Say you have both a terrible headache and a brain tumor. The two are likely related. For someone to come in and help you with your headache, maybe even make it go away, is not the same thing as solving the problem. You still have a brain tumor to deal with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This, crude, analogy is how I think about this larger problem of inequality in the world. Alleviating malnutrition is only part of the problem. It is certainly beyond the scope of Soylent, or any one project, to address global inequality. But my point is that thinking you&#39;re helping by fix the headache, when in fact you probably actually caused the brain tumor, isn&#39;t solving the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lest I seem to sure of myself, let me clarify that I have no idea what the right answer is. I don&#39;t think it&#39;s bad that people are trying to solve world hunger, but I do think it is bad that it often stops here.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2014 20:47:19 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/culture%20and%20society/technology/2014/07/22/an-unsolicited-thought-about-soylent/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/culture%20and%20society/technology/2014/07/22/an-unsolicited-thought-about-soylent/</guid>
        
        
        <category>culture and society</category>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why I meditate and participate in endurance sports</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I ran my first triathlon of the season this past weekend. It was a really fun experience with new friends I&#39;ve made here in Brooklyn. I&#39;ve also been meditating with coworkers and on my own, regularly, for the last 10 plus months. I find a lot in common between these experiences. And I find them instructive for dealing with anxiety about the future, of which there is plenty among my peer group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Endurance sports like distance running, biking, swimming require a lot of mental fortitude. Completing an endurance event is as much a test of mental strength and will power as physical ability. Starting out on mile 1 of a 60 mile bike ride, or turning the corner for mile 20 of a marathon, it is easy to think about what I&#39;ll feel like when I&#39;m done. It&#39;s easy to count backward from the finish line and just convince myself that I&#39;ll keep enduring the pain until it&#39;s over. I sometimes even think the finish line will be worth it, that how crappy I feel in the moment will be rewarded in turn when I finish. But I think that&#39;s a mistake. I find it is much more rewarding to be present. I find much more satisfaction in focusing on how I feel right now. The ride, run or swim become much more calming when I can just focus on how I feel in the moment, enjoying the scenery, focusing on my breath or appreciating the pace I&#39;m keeping up. If I start playing the mental game of &quot;I only have 10 miles to go, which is 5 miles, repeated twice, which is about 30 or 35 minutes, so I should be...&quot; I know I won&#39;t enjoy myself as much. This falsely gives all the credit to the finish, when in fact the finish is only a small fraction of the activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve had similar experiences with meditation. When I first started meditating, I remember having a hard time focusing on the present. My self talk during meditation sessions would primarily be about how I might feel at the end. There was no focus on being present, on learning about the moment I was in. It took me a long time and a lot of practice to understand how to focus on my breath, on how to recognize but not fixate on fleeting thoughts. It was a difficult habit to build, but something I&#39;m glad I worked on. I still work on these habits every time I meditate, but I now understand the goal of focusing on my breath, on allowing myself to learn about my thought patterns and my proclivities through each meditation session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have found these habits to be very helpful in alleviating anxiety in my day to day life as well. Focusing on the future, thinking about next steps, evaluating experiences in terms of future rewards can be very anxiety provoking. I have talked with peers about these feelings too, and I imagine anxiety about the future is prevalent among many people. I have tried my best to focus on the present when moments like this arise for me. Taking pleasure in the moment you&#39;re in, addressing facts and feelings as you know them now, trying your best not to count backward from some imagined future can go a long way in decreasing some of the anxiety caused by a hyper competitive, status minded, fatigue lauding world. There are a lot of things to be said about why we live in a world like this (from perspectives found in economics, sociology, psychology, philosophy, so on and so on), but that&#39;s a discussion about causes. I have found that in the mean time, this tactic of focusing on the present, can be helpful in treating at least this symptom.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2014 19:03:33 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/life/2014/06/09/why-i-meditate-and-participate-in-endurance-sports/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/life/2014/06/09/why-i-meditate-and-participate-in-endurance-sports/</guid>
        
        
        <category>life</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
